(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.1",
"generated_at": "2026-07-30T09:46:34.770735",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
みんな、速報だよ！！
Everyone, breaking news!
なんと、一番くじ hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSSの発売が決定したんだって！！
The Ichiban Kuji Hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS release has been decided!!
ReGLOSSが一番くじ！？これドッキリか何か？
ReGLOSS in an Ichiban Kuji? Is this a prank?
どんなラインナップなんだろ？
I wonder what kind of lineup it'll be!
みんな、運試ししてみてね！
Everyone, try your luck!
なんと、11月13日木曜日より順次発売予定なんだって！ぜひみんなチャレンジしてみてね！
It'll be available sequentially from Thursday, November 13th! Please give it a try!
出来立てホヤホヤのサンプルをスタジオへ用意いただいたます！
We got fresh samples brought right to the studio!
でも、おまえらにはまだ見せられないよ〜
But we can't show you guys yet~
ま、でも、ちょっとだけ教えちゃおっかな〜
Well, maybe I'll let you in on a little secret~
まずは描きおろしイラストを使ったビジュアルボードがあったよね！
First off, there's the visual boards using brand-new illustrations!
しかもイラストの背景にそれぞれにマッチしたモチーフがいろいろ入ってたよね〜
And the backgrounds even have motifs matching each of us!
はじめ「押忍！」って書いてあった！ちょこのっこフィギュア！ホロライブ一番くじではおなじみのやつもあったね
Hajime's says "Oshinin!" Chokonokko figures! The classic Ichiban Kuji item is back!
表情がとっても可愛かった！
The expressions were so cute!
おでかけする時とかにさバッグに忍ばせて一緒に連れて行ってほしくない？
I want people to slip them into their bags when going out and take them along!
この髪の毛のね塗り分けとかグラデーションとかもねすごい小さいのにね綺麗なんだよ〜
Even the hair coloring and gradients are so tiny and pretty!
あとラストワン賞っぽいやつは…デカかったね！
And the Last One prize... was huge!
抱きしめて…眠れる…
You can fall asleep hugging it...
ヒントは以上です！詳細は9月16日一番くじホームページで公開予定！
That's all for the hints! Details will be on the Ichiban Kuji website on September 16th!
お知らせはこれだけじゃない！
That's not all the news!
ReGLOSSの楽曲がミニCDコレクションになりました！
ReGLOSS songs are coming to a mini CD collection!
ガシャポン商品
A Gashapon product,
ホロライブ デベイス リグロス
hololive DEV_IS ReGLOSS's
ミニCDコレクションが販売開始となります！
Mini CD Collection is going on sale!
やったー！
Yay!
こちら小さなCDのようなチャームで
These are tiny CD-like charms,
CD風プレートやジャケットカードを取り出せる仕様になってます！
designed so you can take out the CD-style plates and jacket cards!
すごーい！
Amazing!
ラインナップはデビュー曲「瞬間ハートビート」から
The lineup ranges from our debut song "Shunkan Heartbeat"
1st Album「ReGLOSS」など
to the 1st Album "ReGLOSS,"
シークレットを含む全6種！
featuring 6 types in total including a secret!
どれが出るかはカプセルを開けてのお楽しみ〜！
Which one you get is a surprise when you open the capsule!
ガシャポンのオフィシャルサイトで売ってるお店を検索することもできるのでぜひ参考にしてください！
You can also search for stores selling them on the Gashapon official site, so please check it out!
ということで一番くじもガシャポンもよろしくねー！
So please look forward to both Ichiban Kuji and Gashapon!
ガシャポンしに行こうぜ〜！
Let's go get some Gashapon!
ピースのトップ we are ReGLOSS！
Peace's top, we are ReGLOSS!
このあとはReGLOSS2周年記念配信！
Coming up next is the ReGLOSS 2nd Anniversary stream!
いったい何が起こるんだ！？
What on earth is going to happen!?
たのちみやー！
I'm so excited!
でも配信の前に！
But before the stream,
ReGLOSSの2周年に関するたくさんのお知らせをみんなで振り返っちゃいまーす！
let's look back together at all the announcements regarding ReGLOSS's 2nd anniversary!
じゃあまずは記念グッズ！
First up, anniversary merchandise!
リグロス2周年を記念したグッズがホロライブオフィシャルショップと全国のHMVとHMV&BOOKSの店舗で販売中です！
Commemorative goods for the ReGLOSS 2nd Anniversary are on sale at the hololive official shop and HMV & HMV&BOOKS stores nationwide!
ラインナップはこちら！
Here is the lineup!
おおー！いっぱいある！
Whoa! There's so much!
トートバッグとかめっちゃかわいい！
The tote bags and everything are super cute!
ね、かわいい！Rリグロスだね！
Yeah, cute! It's R for ReGLOSS!
だよね、トートバッグいいね、おしゃんだね！
Right, the tote bag is nice, very stylish!
チェキ全部飾りたいね！
I want to display all the cheki cards!
わかるー！素敵！
I know, right! Lovely!
ランダム缶バッジはHMV限定商品になっているので、ぜひ全国のHMVとHMV&BOOKSにお越しください！
The random tin badges are HMV-limited items, so please visit HMV and HMV&BOOKS nationwide!
お願いしまーす！
Please check them out!
そんなHMVとHMV&BOOKSで本日(9月13日)から開催中のReGLOSS 2nd Anniversaryフェアについても、おさらいでーす！
Now, let's also review the ReGLOSS 2nd Anniversary Fair currently being held at HMV and HMV&BOOKS starting today!
今回のフェアではホロライブグッズを税込み2200円お買い上げごとに限定クリアカードをランダムで1枚プレゼントしちゃいまーす！
In this fair, for every 2,200 yen (tax included) spent on hololive merchandise, we'll give you one random limited clear card!
フェアは10月5日まで！みんな楽しんでねー！
The fair runs until October 5th! Everyone, enjoy it!
そして、2周年記念のボイスも販売中です！
And the 2nd Anniversary Voice packs are also on sale!
今回は旅をコンセプトにしたボイスでシチュエーションボイスとかけあいボイスドラマの2種類があります！
This time, the voices are themed around travel, with two types: situation voices and interactive voice dramas!
どんな内容かといいますと
What's it about, you ask?
なんと旅行の準備をしてる様子であったりとか、あと移動中の様子、なんかをね、リグロスと一緒に旅のワクワクを味わうこと間違いなしのボイスとなっております！ぜひなんどでも聞いて楽しんでください！
It includes scenes of preparing for a trip, traveling on the way, and guarantees you'll experience the excitement of traveling together with ReGLOSS! Be sure to listen and enjoy it as many times as you like!
ということでリグロスの2周年は超超超盛りだくさん！グロッサーもそうでない人もみんなで盛り上がっちゃいましょー！
So ReGLOSS's 2nd anniversary is super, super, super packed! Whether you're a GLOSSER or not, let's all get hyped together!
このあとの2周年記念配信でも何やら特大の発表があるとか！？
Is it true there'll be some massive announcement in the upcoming 2nd anniversary stream!?
え、心当たりがなさすぎる…え、心当たりあって！？すんごい特大のアレだよアレ！
Huh, I have no idea... Wait, you do!? It's that super huge thing, that thing!
皆さん最後まで絶対に見逃さないようにしてね！
Everyone, make sure not to miss a single second until the very end!
それでは配信スタートまでもう少々お待ちくださーい！
Now then, please wait just a little longer until the stream starts!
せーの！リグロスでしたー！！！！
Ready, set! That was ReGLOSS!!!!
ふう...
Ah...
はあ...
ー、超巨大なソーセージが...
So huge... Vienna sausages!
超巨大なソーセージが...
Vienna sausages...
返してくれー！
Give 'em back!
なになに？
What is it?
はあ...
Ah...
みんな気をつけて！
Everyone, be careful!
なんかめっちゃ響きうるさいんだから！
That sounded really loud just now!
やばい！なに？なに？何？感じじゃない。
What? What's going on?
ん。
Mm.
なんかめっちゃ逆ギレ。
That's way too casual!
なに？
What?
ん...
Mm...
こんな、おじちゃの海なんて、うん。泳げないよ。
Like, I can't swim in an ocean of Oji-cha!
泳げないよ。
Swimming...
ううん。
Mm...
待って、気をつけてね。
Wait, be careful, okay?
なんか、うん。
There's...
今目の前に、「後ろを振り向いてはけない。席を立ってはけない」って書いてある。
Right now, in front of us, it says,
「後ろを振り向いてはけない。
"You must not look back.
席を立ってはけない」って書いてある。
You must not leave your seat."
書いてあるの！
It's written there!
もしかしたら振り向いたら
So, if we look back,
死ぬかも！
we might die!
試してみようぜ！
Let's try it out!
やばいやばいやばいやばい！
Wait, wait, wait, wait!
じゃあ、かなで試してみて！
Let's try it for sure!
これまだ夢か、夢っぽいなこれ、まだ。
This still feels like a dream, or dream-like, doesn't it?
全然夢じゃないよ。
It doesn't feel like a dream at all.
夢じゃないよ。
It's not a dream.
お、ていうか、あ、なんか、出てきたよ。
Oh? Oh, look, something appeared!
お、なに？
Oh? What?
えっと、読み上げるね。聞こえますか...ReGLOSSの
"Can you hear me...
聞こえますか...ReGLOSSの皆さん...
ReGLOSS members?
私はこの部屋に封印されたお宝...今...あなたたちの心に直接呼びかけています。
I am the treasure sealed in this room.
なんだって？！
What is this about?!
今から、あなたたちに2年目最後の試練を与えます...みなさんで謎を解いて、
I will now give you the final trial of your second year...
3年目への扉を開けてください。
Please open the door to your third year."
はい。
Got it.
しーりあん。
Shiirian?
謎解きのルールは簡単です...
"The rule for the riddle is simple...
4文字のキーワードを見い出すのです...
Find a four-letter keyword...
おおー。
Ohh.
ただし、席を立ってはけません...
However, you must not leave your seat...
真後ろだけは振り向いてはいけません...
And you must not even turn straight back...
ルールはそれだけです...
That is the only rule..."
え？
Eh?
キーワードがわかったら、一人ずつ順番に読み上げてください...
"Once you know the keyword,
みなさんの絆なら、必ずクリアできるでしょう...
With your bond, you will surely be able to clear it..."
ほう。
Got it.
それでは、開始です。
Now, then,
さあ、みなさんで3年目の扉を開けるのです！
Let's open the door to the third year!
もう3年目始まってる...んですか？
Wait, isn't the third year already starting?
だって！扉開けるも何も、まだ開けられてなかったってこと？
Wait, if it's open, that means it wasn't locked to begin with!
やうほうちょー？
Yau-houchou?
じゃあ、とりあえず、なんか目の前にさ、なんかあるね、ことなんだ？
Wait, there's something right in front of me!
なんか、お？
What is this?
なんか十字架っぽいのが、クロスワードっぽいのが置いてない？
Is this a crossword puzzle?
あ、本当だ！
Ah, that's right!
なんだろう。あんこ？
What could it be? Anko?
あんこ？
Anko?
いや違う、なんかあのバラバラになったひらがなを読んだだけだから、これ何も関係ないやつね。
It's just that the Hiragana are all scattered, so that has nothing to do with it, right?
え、かなでわ、だー。
Eh, Kanade is...
かなではいんぐわ。
Kanade is "ing"!
いんぐ？
"ing"?
それさ、その問題じゃなくてさ、あのクロスワードの埋まってる部分だけじゃん。
Wait, isn't that just the filled-in parts of the crossword puzzle?
じゃあ、ちょっといったんリリカの「ヨコのガギ」の1番いうね。
So, let's look at Lirika's "Yoko no Kagi" number one first, okay?
はい。
Yes.
ある飲み物を作るとき、精米歩合を50%以上60%以下で作るとこう呼ばれる。
"When making a certain drink, if you make it with a rice polishing ratio of 50% to 60% or less, it's called..."
あ！
Ah!
これ、吟醸じゃない？
Isn't this Ginjo?
なんにゃ？
Nan'nya?
リリカさん、
Ririka-san,
ごめん、1ミリも聞いてなかった、ごめん。
sorry, I didn't listen at all, sorry.
吟醸！
Ginjo!
え、1文字、1文字でしょ？
One character, one character, huh?
で、ぎから始まる言葉でうで終わるのだから吟醸じゃないかなって思ったんだけど。
Wait, it starts with "gi" and ends with "u", so I thought it might be Ginjo.
えー、白式？そうなの？中国円。
Hakushiki? Is that so? Chugoku?
え、違うかな？
Or is it different?
え、わかんない。
I don't know.
でも、いまぎから始まってうで終わること他にしらないから、それでいいんじゃない？
I don't know, but since it starts with "gi" and ends with "u", I don't know any other, so isn't that fine?
いいじゃん、いいじゃん。かいちゃいな！
Right, right. Let's just go with that!
かいちゃいな！
Write it!
じゃあ次、ラデンちゃん何かある？
Then next, Ririka-chan, do you have any?
えっと、え、え、えっとねえ。
Uhm, uhm, uhm, well...
え、え、えっと...
Uhm...
ちょっと待って、いま、
Wait, right now,
あの問題が、き、来てる問題がガチすぎて、
the problem coming in is so hardcore
ちょっといま頭が真っ白になっちゃうから、
that my head is totally blank,
ちょっと別のひとに、あ、じゃあカナデどうかな？
so let's pass it to someone else.
えっと、まる1の横が、うーん、
Uh, number one's side is...
コツはタン、タンギング？短かだけと奥深い。
Kotsu is tango-ing? Short and deep.
あ、タンギング？ちゃんたで、
Tangaking? Chanta?
なんかタンギングだと、りこ、た、た、た、た、とかなんじゃないのかなあ。
Like, if it's tangaking, it's riko-? Ta-ta-ta-ta or something?
やばい、全然わかんない。
Yabai, I totally don't get it.
た、た、タンギング。たちつてとなのかなあ。
Ta-ta-tangaking? Tachitsuteto or something?
かなあ。短かけど奥深い。
Or maybe... Short and deep?
わかった、いいこと考えた。
Got it, I've got a good idea.
いったんみんな自分の文章自分の問題読んで、わかるやつは埋めよう。で、わかんないやつを相談する形にしよう。わかった！
Everyone, read your own text and questions, and for the ones you know, let's fill them in, and for the ones you don't, we can consult each other!
そうだね。
Right.
そうそうそう、言ってたあんまり時間がなくなっちゃう気がしちゃうから、
If we stay like this, it feels like we're gonna run out of time,
時間とかあるのかよくわかんないけど。
though I don't know if there's a time limit or anything.
え？あはー、これわかるよー！
Eh? Ah, this is clear!
え？
Eh?
これ、そんにょじょてい？
This... sonnyo jotei?
まる4は、かければいいってこと？
Maru 4 is "If you divide it by four, it's good"?
えもっく、なぎかちゃ？
Emoku nagikachya?
えも？
Emo?
料理の味加減？かちちゅみのこちょ？
Flavor of cooking? Kachichu-mino kotsu?
わかんない。
I don't know!
なんか優しいな。
It feels kind of gentle.
え、かなでわかんたよ！
Eh, I got it!
お、全部わかった？
Oh, really?
いや、全部わかんないけど、まる4がわかるから、
Well, I don't get all of it, but I know maru 4,
なんかキーワードナンバー3がわかりました！
so I figured out keyword number 3!
お、お？
Oh? Oh?
え、これでいいのかな？
Is this good?
キーワードナンバー3は何だったかなでは
What was keyword number three?
えっと、丸4が混ぜ混ぜして食べる料理、
Um, number four is a dish you make by mixing things together,
お好みでコチュジャンをかけてって書いてあったからビビンバで。
and it said to add gochujang to your liking, so "bibimbap".
あー、確かに。
Ah, exactly.
その最後のワードの「ば」でした。
And the last word was "ba".
バカ！
Ba?
バ、バ、バ、バって何だ？
What?
何？バカ。
What? Idiot!
リリカ、まだ何もないじゃん。
Well, Lilyca still has no idea.
まあじゃあ「ば」ね。
Well, then, "ba", right?
うん。
Yeah.
ごめん、リリカねどっちもかんなくて、
I don't get either of them, Lilyca.
何？
What?
あの、4番目「物事の具合をうまく処理すること」。
Um, number four: "To skillfully handle how things are going."
料理の味加減についても言うっていうのがつ、ごめん料理関係は本当にわかんない。
And it also mentions seasoning for food... I really don't get food-related ones.
ええっ！？
Eh?
料理系VTuberじゃなかったの？
Aren't you a cooking VTuber?
もう引退したほうがいいかも、料理系。
I might as well retire from being a cooking channel.
物事の具合をうまく処理することって何？
What is "skillfully handling how things are going"?
し、調理率？
Um... "Shincho-ritsu"? (Cooking rate?)
ほう。
I see.
でも味加減のことそう言うかな？味加減、
Does seasoning have a word like that? Seasoning...
調整？スタ・ベロ？
Chosei? (Adjustment?) Stachbero?
なんかダッシュのやつもあった。
Wait, I have another Dashu.
あじん、あじ、ん。
Aji... Ajim...
これさ、振り返っちゃいけないんだよね。
You aren't supposed to look back at this, you know.
このさ、イラスト何なの？
Um, what is this last illustration?
どこまでちゃ、振り向いていいのはどこまで見ていいものなの？
Where is the limit? How far can you look?
「まっすぐ見るだけだ」って言ってたじゃん。
You said only straight ahead!
横、じゃここはまず、見れるの？
Yoko, can you look?
横はインダ？
Yoko is Inder?
うん。横、えっとリリカ？
Um, Yoko, um, Lilyca?
はい。
Yes.
かなで側の横に何か無い？
Is there something next to the Kannedegawa?
かなで側の横に、なんか、人を殺せそうな
Next to the Kannedegawa, there's...
バットが置いてある。バット？
Oh, there's a bat placed there. A bat?
あとリコーダーがある。
And a recorder around.
バットとリコーダー？
A bat and a recorder?
うん。
Yeah.
バ、バットでいいんだね、それは。
Well, a bat is fine, right?
なんかトゲトゲしたバット、な、本当のバット？
Wait, it's a spiky bat? Is it really a bat?
あの鬼の金棒みたいな感じ？鬼の金棒？
Like an oni's iron club? An oni's iron club?
うん。
Yeah.
なるほど、ありがとう。
I see, thanks.
自分の位置から見えるとも、あー。
Can you see your own position?
で、3番ちょ。
So, number three's...
と、何もわからないじゃん。
I still don't get anything.
なんかかんないのあった？
Is there anything you don't get?
え、なんこれ、アーモンドの香りがしゅる危険な薬品、
Um, what is the name of that dangerous medicine that smells like almonds?
シアン化カリウム、またの名前って何や？
Cyanide... wait, what's its name?
え、むずい。リリカちゃんが滑舌が何て言ったか今わからなかったな。
That's tough. Lilyca's pronunciation was so hard to understand.
え、じゃ、え、アーモンドみたいな香りがしゅる
Cyan... wait, what was it?
危険な薬品、シアン化カリウム、またの名前は何や？
dangerous medicine, cyanide potassium, what's its other name?
せいさんかりとかじゃないの？危険って、あれ。
Isn't it Seisan-kari? Dangerous medicine, wait.
せいさんか、せいさんか！
Seisan-ka? Seisan-ka!
ちょっと、天才やん！え、わかんない。せいさん、せいさんかりか。
She's a genius! Seisankari? Seisankari?
文字数あって る？あっちわ、すごーい！
Is the letter count correct? Ah, it fits!
すごーい！ありがと、じゅん。
Awesome! Thanks, Jun.
おっけー。
Okay.
じゅん？
Jun?
わかんちゃん。
I see.
え、リリカのね、ヒントが、
Lilyca's hint was...
反対側の椅子の背中に書かれている文字が入るってなってて、
that the letters on the back of the opposite chair would fit.
たぶんリリカの反対が番長なんだよね。
So maybe the opposite of Lilyca is Banchou?
だから、ラデちゃんかかなでかどっちか番長の背中見れない？
Can you see Banchou's back from Lade or Kannede?
あ、ラデ見ます。
Ah, Lade, I'll check.
「ん」って書いてあるよ。
It says "un".
「ん」？「ん」？
"Un"? "Un"?
「ん」か、ってことは料理の味加減のやつが、
"Un", so that means the seasoning one is...
2文字目が「ん」なんだけど、それで4文字。
The second letter is "un", making it four letters.
味加減、あじかげん、あじかげん？
Ajikagen... Ajikagen?
物事の具合をうまく処理すること。ばんめん、処理とか、だめだ。カードゲームの何かが全然出てこない。
"Skillfully handling how things are going" - banmen-shori? No, that's wrong, game terms don't come to mind.
4文字じゃん。4文字ね。
Four letters, four letters.
なん、なんだよね。かんかく？
It's... kankaku? (Sense/Feeling)
かんかく？あ、わかったかもしれない！
Kankaku? Ah, I might have figured it out!
あんばい？
Anbai? (Condition/Degree)
あー、そうかも！
Ah, maybe!
ええ、すごーい！
Oh, amazing!
あんばい？
Anbai?
そうかも！かも、わかんない。
Maybe! I don't know, but...
だと、リリカの最初のキーワード、あかも！
And Lilyca's first keyword is... Ah, maybe!
えご、あ、うん、ばうん？
Ego? Ego... um, ba-un?
え？何それ、え、なに？
Huh? What is that?
そのキーワードね、あ、そうね、並べたときに。
When you line up the keywords, right?
番長はあと何が分かってない？
Banchou, what else do you not know?
えっと、4番だけわかんないんだけど、うん、うん。
Um, I only don't get number four, but...
あの、ヒントは反対側の椅子の背だから、リリカ？
Um, the hint is behind the opposite chair, so Lilyca's...
の背中？問題は、
Back? The question is...
ストリートダンス、クランプでの特徴的な振り付け、「ストンプ」「チェストポップ」あと一つは？
"Characteristic choreography in street dance (Kurump), Stomp, Chest Pop, and what is the last one?"
なんだろう、リリカの背中を見てあげて。
What could it be? Look at Lilyca's back for me.
おい、誰も見ねえのかよ！
Hey, nobody's looking at it!
リリカ、リリカ背中見れないもん。
Look at Lilyca's back!
待って、リリカの背中見たらいいんだね？そう。
Wait, you just need to look at Lilyca's back, right?
「す」。
Su.
「す」、がはいる、ダンスのやつ？
"Su", it starts with "Su" - is that a dance thing?
ステップ？
Stepp?
違う、それはニューグコー？わかんない。
No, that's Jugoo, right? I don't know.
ステップ、す、スクー、
Stepp... Su, Suku...
す、す、す、すみません！
Su, Su... Sorry!
すみません！すみません！
Sorry! Sorry!
え、全然わかんないな。
I totally don't get it.
すみません、ちょっとぶた切ってしまって申し訳ないんですが、
Sorry, I butchered the stage, I'm so sorry.
ラデちゃんにもいこう。
Let's ask Lade.
誰か私の背中に書かれている文字を呼んでほしいです。
Somebody please read the text written on my back!
Bです。
It's B.
B？
B?
うん、ば、ばびぶべぼのび？
B, as in "Ba-Bi-Bu-Be-Bo"?
そう。
Yeah.
おけい。
Okay.
どんな問題？えっとね、江戸時代に
What kind of problem? Um, Edo period...
こそでのでいろとして流行した青色の名前、宝石ラピスラズリの和名や、ガラスの昔の呼び方が含まれてて
A blue color that became popular for kosode back then, including the Japanese name for lapis lazuli and the old word for glass,
がちすぎだろこれ。
this is way too serious.
ガチすぎ。
Way too serious.
問題が難しすぎて一瞬頭がパーンってなっちゃった。
The puzzle was so hard my brain just went pop for a second.
ビが最初入ってるんだ。
There's a "bi" at the beginning.
ここはシュなのか？
Is this part "shu"?
美白とかビコ、ビコ、コ白
Fair skin or biko, biko, kohaku...
最初のひと文字がコなんだよね。コビ？
The first letter is "ko", right? "Kobi"?
コビリ、コビリ
Kobiri, kobiri.
やばい、全然わかんないんだけど。
Oh no, I totally don't get it at all.
え、わかんないじゃん。
Huh, you don't get it either?
コビと？
Kobi and...?
こう、コビ？コバルトブルー？
Ko, kobi? Cobalt blue?
違う。
No.
あ、でも多分これかな。
Ah, but this is probably it.
あ、イングってなるんだけどシュが入って言ってたじゃん。
"Ah, ing", but you said "shu" goes in there, right?
で、アームシュイングかニャーみたいな。
So maybe arm-swing or something?
え、でもわからん。そんな言葉私ら知らんか。
Eh, but I don't get it. Words like that are beyond us.
生み出しちゃった、その言葉を。
You invented that word.
生み出しちゃったか。
You really invented it.
他にバンチョーから連ちゃんでなんかヒントになりそうなものない？
Isn't there anything else from Bancho that could be a hint if we connect them?
この文字をこの問題解ければいけるかもなみたいな。
Like, if we solve this problem with these letters, we might be able to do it.
で、セ、リリナとリリナのあいだにあるのはトゲトゲのバットだったんだよね。
And between se and lirina and lirina, there was a spiky bat.
トゲトゲのバットとレコーダー、トゲトゲのバットってさ、なんかトゲトゲのバット以外の言い方ってない？
A spiky bat and a recorder. Is there any other way to say spiky bat?
金棒。
Kanabo.
あいだが2文字めにうんが来る。
And there's an "un" in the second letter of the middle word.
うんが来る？
An "un" comes in?
コンボじゃない？
Isn't it combo?
あ、これじゃない？
Oh, isn't it this?
コンボって言うよね。
They call it combo, right?
待って、ちょっと待って、始め最初の一文字自分で書いて間違ってる成長ある？
Wait, hold on. Did I write the very first letter myself and get the growth wrong?
え？
Eh?
え、この色で写真を加工すると
Eh, if you process a photo with this color,
エモくなり がち。
it tends to get emotional (sepia).
セピア。
Sepia.
えだよね。合ってるよね。
Eh, right? That's correct, right?
いやわかんない。
I don't know anymore.
え、もともとはイカ趣味のこちょらあったって。
Eh, originally there was a squid hobby...
モノトーンとか？モノクロ？
Monotone or something? Monochrome?
いや、でもシャンモチなんだよな。
No, but it's shammot.
でセピアラッチョ持って、しかも生臭カリウムもつながるしやん。
And it has sepia ratty, and it even connects with raw stinky potassium.
で、あのパーティー会場で誓うハンマーの
And, um, the hammer sworn at party venues,
ピコピコハンマー？
Pikopiko hammer?
めっちゃ埋まってるんだよ。
It's super filled in.
で、そのダンスのやつだけわかんないんだよね。
And I just don't get the dance one.
で、あから始まってシュがつくんだったら、まあシュイングにはなるだろうなっていうので、
So, if it starts with "a" and ends with "shu", it's probably "swing", so...
あ、1文字やん。
Ah, it's one letter.
まあ、あで
Well, with "a"—
あ、じゃあ1文字だったら腕かなみたいな。
Ah, if it's one letter, maybe "arm" or something like that.
思うじゃん。
You'd think.
アームってこと？
You mean "arm"?
そう。
Yeah.
で、それで作長のワードは何になるの？
So what does Bancho's word become with that?
キーワードは無になる。
The keyword becomes "mu".
なるほど。
I see.
あ、バームってこと？
Ah, you mean "balm"?
いや、アルバムじゃねえか！
No, isn't it album?!
じゃあアルバムじゃねえか！
Then it is an album!
あ、バームの中、うの中に入る言葉なんかあるかな？
Ah, inside "balm", is there any word that goes inside "u"?
アジバームとか。
Ajibalm or something?
アジバーム。
Ajibalm.
アセバーム。
Asebalm.
アセバーム！
Asebalm!
アセバームいいね。
Asebalm is good.
いいねなのお？
What do you mean "good"?
キーワードナンバー2なんだけど、ナンバー2か。
Keyword number 2 though, number 2.
ルーのような気がしています。
I feel like it's "ru".
いや、今もうその話してるでしょ。
No, we're already talking about that!
なんでだよ。
Why?!
いや、なんかあれだ、難しく考えすぎてたんだな。
Man, I was thinking about it too hard.
もう、もういいかもしれない。
I guess that's enough.
あ、じゃあ特にその、あの、ラピスラズリの和名が分かったとかじゃなくて、なんとなくルな気がする。
Ah, so not particularly because we figured out the Japanese name for lapis lazuli, but it just somehow feels like "ru".
いや、たぶんね、コビールリのような気がするんだけど、あの、ラデン側にすごい問題が起きていて、何が問題かっていうと、
Well, I feel like it's kobiriri, but, um, there's a huge problem on Raden's side. What's the problem?
ラデンの周りに色々ヒントがあるのはね、なんとなく分かってるんだけど、
We kind of know there are various hints around Raden,
目が悪すぎてさ、何を表してるのか全く分からないんだよね。
but my eyesight is so bad that I have no idea what they represent.
何が、何があるのか周りに全く見えない。
I can't see what's around at all.
え、ラデンちゃんの隣にはピストルがあるよ。
Eh, there's a pistol next to Raden-chan.
ピストルね？
Pistol?
うん。あとなんかもう一個ない？
Yeah. And isn't there another one?
なんか、マジで目が悪くて
Seriously, my eyesight is so bad—
そうだ、ラデンさん、目が悪いっぽいんだけど、
Right, Raden-san seems to have bad eyesight,
なんか大股なのか羊なのかになんか乗っかってる。
and it's riding on something like a big thigh or a sheep.
え、牛じゃない？これ。
Eh, isn't it a cow? This.
これ牛なの？
This is a cow?
広い草原みたいなところで黒い物体と白い物体がフュージョンしてる。
In a place like a wide grassy field, a black object and a white object are fusing.
いや、じゃあ人が、人が大股に乗ってんじゃねえこと。
Then it's not a person riding on a big thigh, right?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
キーワードナンバー2はルです。
Keyword number 2 is "ru".
全く想像つかない。てか後ろを向けないから見れないんだけど。
I can't imagine it at all. Plus I can't look back so I can't see it.
もういいよ、ラディグロス、俺らアルバムで行こうぜ！よく分かんないけど。
Forget it, Radigloss, let's go with "album"! Even if we don't really get it.
いや、なんかぽいよね。ぽいよね。
Well, kind of looks like it. It looks like it.
じゃあ、キーワード1、あ。
So, keyword 1: "a".
キーワード2、る。
Keyword 2: "ru".
キーワード、ナンバー3、ば。
Keyword number 3: "ba".
キーワードナンバー4、む。
Keyword number 4: "mu".
せーの！アルバム！
Ready, go! Album!
どうや？
How is it?
これどうや？
How about this?
もう振り回しちゃいけないやつだな、これは。
You shouldn't be swinging this around anymore.
まだじゃない？
Isn't it still early?
振れ、振れ！
Swing it, swing it!
振り回せよ！振り回せ！振り回しちゃえ！
Swing it around! Swing it! Just swing it!
なんかある！
There's something!
何何何！？
What, what, what!?
何これ！？何これ！？え、なにこれ！？
What is this!? What is this!? Eh, what's this!?
え、なにこれ、なにこれ、これこれ！
Eh, what's this, what's this, this!
じゃあちょっと宝箱何買ってさっきの呪文もう一回唱えるか。
Let's open the treasure box and chant that spell again.
なんだけ、なんだけ、
What was it, what was it,
エグロスのアルバム！
ReGLOSS's album!
行くよ！
Here we go!
せーの、アルバム！
Ready, go! Album!
どうだ？
How is it?
脱出成功！！
Escape successful!!
こんな難しい問題生でやらせんなよ！
Don't make us do such a hard puzzle live!
危ねえ！
That was close!
こけないとこがさ、お茶目じゃん。
Not falling over is cute, right?
おちゃっぴー！
Silly goose!
え、なにこれ！？なんか解除された！
Eh, what is this!? Something unlocked!
なんかニューアニバーサリーって感じあるね。
It feels like a new anniversary.
ハッピーアニバーサリー！アニバーサリーね！
Happy anniversary! It's anniversary!
いや、アニバーサリーばっかりじゃん！ハッピー！おめでたいね！
Man, it's all about anniversaries! Happy! How celebratory!
なんかさ、この配信前にスタッフさんが「いや、簡単、すごい簡単だから」と、おー！とか言ってて、いざ難しいてなったら、大喜びみたいな。
Before this stream, the staff said, "No, it's easy, super easy," and we went "Ooh!", but when it turned out to be hard, they were overjoyed.
美術系って受けてるのかと思ってびっくりした。よかった！
I was surprised, thinking it was an art test. Good thing!
よかった！
Phew!
それぞれがちょっと得意っぽい分野の問題になってたのはよかったね。そうだね、だったりね。
It was nice that the questions were in areas each of us is somewhat good at. That's right, yeah.
知らねえよ！すっごいやることもなかった
I didn't know! There was so much to do,
ビビンバで終わっちゃった
It ended with bibimbap!
ということで、皆さん、もうお分かりかと思いますけれども、まずはこちらの映像をご覧ください。
With that said, everyone, I'm sure you already know, but first, please take a look at this footage.
staring into your eyes make me feel alive
それは始まりの合図
That's the starting signal.
are you ready for this？
Are you ready for this?
柔らかな風 ほら、春めいて
A gentle breeze, look, turning spring-like.
共鳴するファンファーレ
A resonating fanfare.
桜花爛漫 染める 桃色
Cherry blossoms in full bloom, dyeing everything pink.
バッド落ちと...
Bad fall...
さっきの問題の難しかった話しながら笑いながら、すみません、VTRの裏でちょっと話してました。すみません。
While laughing about how hard the previous question was, sorry, we were talking behind the scenes during the VTR. Sorry.
はい、ということでですね、なんと！
Yes, and with that, amazingly!
ReGLOSSのセカンドアルバムが11月12日に発売決定！
ReGLOSS's 2nd album is confirmed for release on November 12th!
イヤー！やったー！
Yay! Woohoo!
アルバムのタイトルは「Snapshot」。写真のように日々の暮らしに寄り添い、時に、え、共に時を重ねていけるようなそんなアルバムになっています。
The album title is "Snapshot". It's an album that, like a photograph, stays close to your daily life and allows us to share time together.
はい、今回のアルバムはホロライブ公式ECサイト限定の完全生産限定盤と通常盤の2種類あります。
Yes, this album comes in two versions: a completely limited production edition exclusive to the official hololive EC site, and a regular edition.
完全生産限定盤は海外のおもちゃを彷彿とさせるブリスターパック仕様で、
The completely limited production edition features a blister pack design reminiscent of overseas toys,
CDの他にアルバムの衣装と同じデニム風の色味が可愛いカメラ型タルトケース！
along with the CD, a cute camera-shaped tablet case with the same denim-like color as the album costumes!
リリースされたばかりのソロ曲のビジュアルを使用したソロシリーズカードセット！
A solo series card set featuring visuals of the newly released solo songs!
そして複製コメント入りランダムプロフィールカード1枚がランダムでついてきますよ！
And one random profile card with a duplicated comment will be included at random!
通常盤は全国流通もします！初回プレス限定の封入特典としてランダムミニカードが1枚封入されています。
The regular edition will also be distributed nationwide! As a first-press limited enclosure bonus, one random mini card is included.
取扱いはSNSや今後随時発表される過去販売店の情報をチェックしてください！
For availability, please check SNS and information on past retailers to be announced later!
ホロライブ公式ECサイトの予約はこの時間からスタート！
Reservations on the hololive official EC site start from this time!
おおー！
Ooh!
予約ページのリンクが表示されていると思いますのでチェックしてください！
I think the link to the reservation page is displayed, so please check it!
さらに店舗別特典のラインナップを公開しちゃいます！
Furthermore, we are revealing the lineup of store-specific bonuses!
Amazonなど詳しい情報は後日公開予定です。
Detailed information such as Amazon will be announced at a later date.
またこのアルバムに収録されている楽曲はデジタルでの配信も予定しておりますのでお楽しみに！よろしくお願いします！
Also, the songs included in this album are scheduled for digital streaming, so please look forward to it! Thank you!
そしてセカンドアルバムのリリースを記念して今年もリリースイベントの開催が決定しました！
And to commemorate the release of the 2nd album, a release event has been decided to be held this year as well!
期間内に対象商品をHMV&BOOKS online、HMV&BOOKS店舗にて全額うちきんでご予約いただいた方の中から抽選でご招待！
Those who pre-order eligible products in full at HMV&BOOKS online or HMV&BOOKS stores during the period will be invited by lottery!
今回は第1部リリイネ、第2部ラデハジとなっております。
This time, Part 1 is Lyrine, and Part 2 is Radehaji.
お応募まってまーす！
We look forward to your applications!
staring into your eyes make me feel alive
それは始まりの合図
That's the starting signal.
待って、ちょい待って。初めてっち、ライブ会場向かってる途中じゃなかったっけ？
Wait, hold on a sec. Weren't we on our way to the live venue for the first time?
え、そうだっけ？
Eh, is that so?
いや、違うよ！ライブ会場行くって話だったじゃん！
No, that's wrong! We were talking about going to the live venue!
そっか！
I see!
ということで、この後、この後ですね、ミニライブ！
So, after this, right after this, a mini-live!
本日MVが公開された「アワータイム・イエロー」のパフォーマンスもあるので最後まで見てくださいね！
There will also be a performance of "Our Time Yellow" whose MV was released today, so please watch until the end!
ライブじゃも、まだ、中継発表か、あるちょか！
Also for the live, is there a broadcast announcement or something?!
まだまだ2周年記念配信は始まったばかり！
The 2nd anniversary stream has only just begun!
ほな、急いでライブ会場にいらっしゃい！
Well then, hurry on over to the live venue!
可愛い！
So cute!
レッツゴー！行くぞー！
Let's go! Let's go!
どういうステップ？これ
What kind of step is this?
どうするんだっけ
How does it go again?
ここライブ会場じゃない？
Isn't this the live venue?
でか！
So big!
まっしろ！
Pure white!
うわ待って、眩しっ！
Whoa wait, so bright!
やばい、やばい！
Oh no, oh no!
行け行け行けガー！ガー！ガー！
Go go go, gah, gah, gah!
先陣切ろっか？
Shall we take the lead?
切んないよ
No way.
ちょっと待って…やばい、ちょ、足がつった
Wait a minute... oh no, wait, my leg cramped.
え、大丈夫？
Eh, are you okay?
やばい、ちょ、これ、足上げようか
Oh no, wait, should we raise our legs?
え、うそ！？
Eh, really!?
痛っ！痛っ！
Ow! Ow!
草生えた
Lol.
むっちゃ汗だからさ、また買ってもらおうぜ
We're sweating so much, let's get some more.
そうだね
That's right.
いやもう、変な汗かきすぎてもうなんか、冷や汗というか冷や汗が止まらなかったよね
Man, sweating so much weird sweat, like cold sweat just wouldn't stop.
難しかった？
Was it difficult?
いやなんかね、やっぱ予想外だった、なんか、なんか謎解きみたいなのが出てくるのかなって思ってた
Well, y'know, it was totally unexpected. I thought some riddle-solving stuff would come up.
普通に雑学というか知識系だったね
It was just regular trivia and knowledge stuff, huh.
すっごいびっくりした
I was super surprised.
知識を初めに求めんなよ
Don't demand knowledge right off the bat!
漢字で出すじゃん
They put it in kanji, though.
常識でさ、常識、常識、常識
Common sense, common sense, common sense...
で、清少納言にちょっと答えられなかったの、小野小町は、なんか、アーモンドに小野小町では、清少納言っつって、最初見たことあるの
And we couldn't answer Sei Shonagon. Ono no Komachi was like... wait, have you ever seen Sei Shonagon with almonds?
ありえへんもん
That's impossible.
そうね、知ってるやつあんまないもんな
True, there aren't many things we know.
うん
Yeah.
はぁ…そろそろか
Haah... Is it about time?
何歌う？
What should we sing?
え、今から決める感じ？
Eh, we're deciding right now?
カラオケじゃないんだからさ、ノリなんだけど、何歌う？
This isn't karaoke! It's just a vibe, but what should we sing?
何歌う？何にしようかね
What should we sing? What should we make it?
踊りながら歌えるやつがいいんじゃない？
Wouldn't something we can sing while dancing be good?
踊りながらだから、ハードル高いことするね
Dancing while singing? That's setting the bar pretty high!
はぁ…
Haah...
遠目で仰いだ雲の上
Looking up from a distance above the clouds,
ベールに包まれたあの星まで
veiled up to that distant star.
流れ落ちてきた光に跨って
Straddling the light that fell down,
一緒に浮遊飛行しよう
let's float and fly together.
Look out 無数の星たちが
Look out, countless stars
意気としてステップ刻んでいる
are joyfully carving out steps.
我が物顔で招くアイソレーション クール決める絶対零度
Selfish isolation, absolute zero looking cool.
冴えない夢にはお愛想
No need for boring dreams,
花咲く笑顔が似合いそう
a blooming smile suits you well.
イエローナイフみたいなパラダイス
A paradise like a Yellowknife,
踊ろうよ under the starlight
let's dance under the starlight.
流れに身を委ねて
Surrendering to the flow,
ただ漂うだけの updraft
just drifting on an updraft.
キミだけのプレイリスト
A playlist just for you,
mild flow 耳元まで運ぶよ
carried gently to your ears.
ドンピシャなモーション
Spot-on motion,
don't be shy！ laki mode
don't be shy! Laki mode.
闇を照らすオーロラ
An aurora illuminating the darkness,
言葉いらずのオンリーワン
the one and only with no need for words.
踊っていたいずずっと
I want to keep dancing, always,
またとないこの日を
this day that will never come again.
降り注ぐ plasma
Pouring plasma,
キミがいれば プラスワン mm
if you're here, plus one mm.
色濃く映そう ビビッドなハイライト
Let's project vividly, vivid highlights.
病みつきになる dance dance
An addictive dance, dance.
灰になるまで愛す 愛す
Loving you until it turns to ash.
寝ても覚めても 華やぐトワイライト
Even asleep or awake, a glamorous twilight.
煌めいたら nice nice
If it shines, nice, nice.
纏う光 ice ice
Draping light, ice, ice.
色濃く映そう ビビッドなハイライト
Let's project vividly, vivid highlights.
病みつきになる dance dance
An addictive dance, dance.
灰になるまで愛す 愛す
Loving you until it turns to ash.
寝ても覚めても 華やぐトワイライト
Even asleep or awake, a glamorous twilight.
煌めいたら nice nice
If it shines, nice, nice.
纏う光 ice ice
Draping light, ice, ice.
擦り付いた胸の奥
Deep within my chest,
愛してやまないもの
things I can't stop loving,
疑うことも知らないまま
remaining unaware of even how to doubt.
そうやり遂げる覚悟はできてるよ
I'm ready to see it through.
キミだけキミの未来だ
You alone are your own future.
SUPER DUPER お得意中の十八番なら 限界まで踊ろうよ
SUPER DUPER, let's dance to our limit!
誰が何と言おうと気にすんな見せたれかいじょう
Show them, no matter what anyone says!
踏んだり蹴ったりさえも楽しむだけ
Enjoy even the ups and downs,
美しい声を響かせ合って
making our voices resonate together.
うつむいた世界を変えてみせよ
Let's change this downcast world.
一期一会も いちご一会そう添えて
Treasure every single encounter,
新鮮を抱いていて
holding onto freshness.
今宵なく恋したメロディと
With the melody I've fallen in love with tonight,
出逢えなくてはなしだぜプリーカー
we can't go on without meeting—please come!
もう泣くキミとの境界線を声でリプレイ
Replay the boundary line with the crying you.
SUPER DUPER お得意中の十八番なら 限界まで踊ろうよ
SUPER DUPER, let's dance to our limit!
誰が何と言おうと気にすんな見せたれかいじょう
Show them, no matter what anyone says!
踏んだり蹴ったりさえも楽しむだけ
Enjoy even the ups and downs,
美しい声を響かせ合って
making our voices resonate together.
うつむいた世界を変えてみせよ
Let's change this downcast world.
大きな声で叫べば Favorite!
Shout it loud, favorite!
大きな声でこのまま連れ去って
Take me away just like this with a loud voice.
大きな声でこのままでいたいよ
I want to stay like this with a loud voice,
エイジ・ブリージ 踊ろうよ エイジ・ブリージ
Easy breezy, let's dance, easy breezy!
それぞれ異なって勝ちこんまいな スマホ覗きよりもち笑えば
Different values clash, but let's smile instead.
よそ見の仲間消すばばいばいさ
Say goodbye to looking away.
もっと話したい時によりばかそわき
Let's talk more when the time is right.
運命 共同体 手を繋いで
Destiny dancing together,
行く先のアイラク
going toward our bliss.
分かち合える エンドレス 心地
Let's share this endless passion together.
Reach the top yeah!
絶対絶対絶対的キキのチュー
Absolute victory in our hands.
今は自由気まま 水色なユニバース
Free, vibrant, in a pale universe.
限界突破 引き付けるミラクルコウ
Breaking through boundaries, a miraculous melody.
Favorite!
Dangerous Marine Smell Ahoy
(これ開けたら君たちにななんて言ってあげるべきかな...?)
(I wonder what I should say...)
(「探してたのはそ・ん・ち・ょ・お?」うーん...)
(Were you looking for Senchou?)
(「ああん❤そんなにがっついちゃだめだぜ❤」かな?)
(Ahhn, don't cling so tight!)
(「お宝より魅力的な”モノ”見つけちまった...?」いいじゃない❤)
(You've found something even better than treasure!)
誘うガーネットの赤
Garnet red enticing you,
極上の海賊の秘宝
The supreme pirate's treasure...
それは私
It's me.
艶が溢れ漂う 匂いをどうかし恐がらわないで
Overflowing with allure, don't fear the fragrance.
開けてみて
Open it up!
(❤Ahoy❤)
(Ahoy!)
Sexy世界一 Superピチピチ
Sexy in this world, super peachy-peachy!
ぶっちぎり船長捕まえたくなりたい?
Caught the captain, don't you want to?
You're gonna get the treasure Maybe tasting me
私の甘さが 欲しいでしょ
You want my sweetness, don't you?
(Ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
秘宝の鍵を 優しく刺して
Gently slide the key to the treasure!
(Ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
宝庫の扉 マジで早く開けて
Hurry and open the vault's door!
(❤Ahoy❤)
(Ahoy!)
じれったい貴方の手 海図にこぼす甘いため息のTease (Yeah...)
Sweet sighs of tease spilled on your map... (Yeah!)
純紅のバラが しおれる前に
Before the scarlet roses wither away...
WE WILL SAIL THE SEVEN SEAS
SUMMER SUN SMILE
SHINING OCEAN OF MARINE
NOW PLEASE GRANT MY DEAREST DREAM
OPEN UP THIS BOX OPEN IT RIGHT NOW OR I WILL SCREAM
(さもないと)
(Or else...)
AAAAAAAAAAAAAAA!!!! (あけろおおおお)
Aaaaaah, open up!
泣く子も黙る naughty 悩殺ビーム
Even crying kids fall silent to my naughty, captivating beam!
キミたちももう我慢 できなくなない? (kaboom...)
You guys can't hold back anymore, right? (Kaboom...)
YOU’RE GONNA OWN THE PLEASURE Maybe love of me?
You're gonna own the pleasure, maybe love of me?
私の全てを 手に入れて
Take all of me into your hands!
(Ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
金銀財宝
Gold coins and treasure...
(Ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
はした金でしょ
Are fleeting things!
(Ah-hoy!! da-ba-da-boi)
しわしわになってしまう 誰か助けて
Somebody save me before my treasures dry out!
それではいつもの挨拶で
Let's start with our usual greeting, okay?
いつもの挨拶大丈夫?息途切れてない?大丈夫?
Is everyone's breath okay?
いつもの挨拶からいきますよ!
Let's go with the usual greeting!
リジャートプ We are...
Ready, pop! We are...
ReGLOSS!
はい、ということで
So, um...
ラッキーモードとスーパーデューパーそしてプズズファンク曲を聴いていただきました!
We sang Lucky Mode, Super Duper, and PuzPuz!
B.A.D.S.でーす
B.A.D.S.!
皆さん盛り上がってますか?!
Are you all getting hyped?!
イエーイ!
Yeah!
ありがとうございます
Thank you very much.
早すぎでしか
That was quick!
はい、よろしくお願いします
Please!
はいチューボチュレ、えちょうなん?あ、なんかわ、うん、最近だからね
Hai, Chubo-chure. Eh, Chou-nan?
1個しトレンドにいたってえ?!
Tik Tok trending right now!
マジで?!
No way!
え、そんな有名な…有名じゃないんだろ!
Is it that famous?
ね、たくさんポストしてくださってありがとうございます!
Thank you so much for posting so many videos!
引き続きよろしくお願いします!
Please keep it up!
でもさ、久しぶりにさラッキーモードとスーパーデューパーなんか歌ったね
It's been a while since we sang Lucky Mode and Super Duper.
しかも今回、こうなんていうのこういうのミックスバージョンみたいなさ
And this time, what do you call it? A mix version?
ぜんちょうのスーパーデューパーは久しぶり
Super Duper was a while ago...
金音と青くんで一緒に歌っていただいたんですけど
Kanade and Ao-kun sang it together!
そう、なんかちょっと久しぶりに聞けて嬉しくなくなっちゃったな
We were so happy to be able to sing it again after all this time!
え、久しぶりぐらいか、確かにね1周年依頼…ラッキーモもひどみいない
How long has it been? Probably since the 1st anniversary?
そうかも…
That's true.
最後のポーズ何だったの、みんなこれ?
What was everyone's last pose?
これ?ちょうなん?
This? Cho-nan?
え?最后ポーズ何、当ててほしい、これで
We want everyone to guess what it is!
なんだと思う?当ててみな。え、社長これマジで何?
What do you think it is?
みんなで決めたのよ!ひよこから決めたの!
Everyone else decided it!
あ、これはわかる!
Ah, that I get!
これわかる。え、これは?
And what about this?
鳴き声は?ピュピュ?
The crying voice?
コケコッコー!
Koke-kokko?
それには鶏じゃん!
That's a chicken!
あ、でもひよこだ、ちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅちゅ!
It's a chick! Chirp-chirp-chirp!
これわかりやすいんじゃない?
That's easy to understand!
鳴き声は?ぴょんぴょんぴょんぴょん!
The crying voice? Pyon-pyon!
本当か?
Really?
泣くかな?あ、でもペンギンって言ってる!おっしゃ!
Do they cry? They say penguin!
で、りりちゃんも?
And Ririka's?
悪いねこちゃんだな!
Wild, fierce cat!
激チメのねこちゃん!
A fierce cat!
可愛いですよね!
Cute, right?
はい、なんと最後はねみんなでそれぞれの動物を表現しておりました!
So at the end, we each expressed our animals.
なんか、ぽっと夢見やだな
Somehow, it feels like a sudden daydream.
本当、色々と聞けると思うので楽しみにしていてください！
Really, I think you'll be able to hear all sorts of things, so please look forward to it!
はい、皆さん息は大丈夫そうですか？
So everyone, does your breathing seem okay?
ですか？
Is it?
ギリ大丈夫でもいけそう？いけそう？ん。
Even if it's just barely okay, can you make it? Can you make it? Hmm.
はい、ということでね、じゃあまだ、まだまだ終わりませんよ！まだ、もしかしたらあるかもしれないですよ！
Yes, and with that, hey, we're still not done yet! There might still be more!
はい、ハッシュタグこれもお願いします！いっぱい呟いてください！ReGLOSS 2周年！
Yes, hashtag, please use this too! Please tweet a lot! ReGLOSS 2nd Anniversary!
はい、じゃあ次の曲、何ですか？次の曲、なんと、本日公開初解禁の、あの曲！
Yes, so what's the next song? The next song is, surprisingly, that song, unveiled and premiered today for the first time!
うわー！じゃあ、立ち位置につきますか？はい！
Whoa! Well then, shall we get into position? Yes!
すすすす、何の曲かな？何の曲かな？
Su-su-su-su, what song is it? What song is it?
それでは、聞いてください。アワータイムイエロー
With that, please listen to it. Hourtime Yellow.
ソラオボエで挑む人生ゲーム
Playing the game of life by ear
言い訳めいたハートに従って
Following a heart full of excuses
現実 半即興なプロットです
Reality is a half-improvised plot
取り憑かれるオーバーな芝居
Possessed by an over-the-top performance
世渡り上手なあの子はね (hey)
That smooth-talking girl is, you see (hey)
二度と被った猫外せない
Unable to ever take off her fake persona
痛みを覚えてしまった magician
A magician who has learned the pain
手の中は未だ明かさない
Still hiding what's in her hands
yellow yellow ゼロからループ点滅するピリオド
Yellow, yellow, a period blinking in a loop from zero
yellow yellow 染まる赤い化粧
Yellow, yellow, dyed in red makeup
i wonder if i can make it or not
例えツキに見放されても
Even if luck abandons me
no worries 私には私がついている
No worries, I have myself by my side
宵が覚めるまであと少しだけ真のi捉える残像
Just a little longer until the night wears off, capturing the true 'I' in afterimages
slow and steady wins the race
次の季節を越えて blooming blooming
Crossing over to the next season, blooming, blooming
どうかこの声を止めないで
Please don't stop this voice
hourtime yellow yellow
let it blow let it blow
ずっと stay gold
Always stay gold
hourtime yellow yellow
let it blow let it blow
let's enjoy the moment
絡まってる蜘蛛の糸
Tangled spider threads
it happens all the time
踊らされたって構わない
It doesn't matter if I'm being danced around
夜を日に継いで時を編んで明け暮れて
Weaving time day and night from dusk till dawn
always be honest
永遠に変わらないもの
Something that never changes eternally
yellow yellow
手を取り合えばそこに理由はいらない
If we hold hands, we don't need a reason
yellow yellow
染まる赤い化粧
Dyed in red makeup
a smile suits you best
幾つになっても changeless
Changeless no matter how old we get
希望 夢は人知れず
Hopes and dreams, unknown to others
歪で数奇な運命や
Distorted and whimsical destinies
人生ごと受け入れる
Accepting life itself
心機一転 二転 三転 詠んで 第五感で lock on
A fresh start, a second, third turn, reciting, locking on with the fifth sense
右見て 左見て pause 前だけ向いて go on
Look right, look left, pause, look straight ahead and go on
歌い続ける 24/7
Singing continuously 24/7
終着点は eden or heaven?
Is the destination Eden or Heaven?
no time to waste
“今”を信じている
Believing in the 'now'
最後のフィナーレまで共に進め
Advancing together until the final finale
宵が覚めるまであと少しだけ真のi捉える残像
Just a little longer until the night wears off, capturing the true 'I' in afterimages
slow and steady wins the race
次の季節を越えて blooming blooming
Crossing over to the next season, blooming, blooming
どうかこの声を止めないで
Please don't stop this voice
hourtime yellow yellow
let it blow let it blow
ずっと stay gold
Always stay gold
hourtime yellow yellow
let it blow let it blow
let's enjoy the moment
絡まってる蜘蛛の糸
Tangled spider threads
it happens all the time
踊らされたって構わない
It doesn't matter if I'm being danced around
夜を日に継いで時を編んで明け暮れて
Weaving time day and night from dusk till dawn
always be honest
永遠に変わらないもの
Something that never changes eternally
yellow yellow
手を取り合えばそこに理由はいらない
If we hold hands, we don't need a reason
yellow yellow
染まる赤い化粧
Dyed in red makeup
a smile suits you best
幾つになっても changeless
Changeless no matter how old we get
hourtime yellow yellow
let it blow let it blow
ずっと stay gold
Always stay gold
hourtime yellow yellow
let it blow let it blow
let's enjoy the moment
一振りのダンス、瞬の視線、一拍の鼓動
With every single dance, every fleeting gaze, every beat of the pulse
一秒一秒が永遠に鳴り響く
Every single second echoes on eternally
ReGLOSSが描いていく“今”を切り取った一枚一枚の連続
A continuous series of snapshots capturing the 'now' ReGLOSS draws
そのすべてが連なり観る人の記憶に焼きついていく
All of it connects and etches itself into the viewers' memories
2025.12.16 Tue. Flashpoint ReGLOSS 1st Live
ARIAKE ARENA
それぞれの光が響き合い、世界をかたちづくる
Their respective lights resonate, shaping the world
ReGLOSSはその瞬間を音楽とダンスで伝える
ReGLOSS conveys that moment through music and dance
みんな見た見た見た？
Did you guys see that?!
ということでね、みんな見た？見た？見た？
That's right, everyone, did you see it? Did you see it?
やばい！12月16日、有明アリーナにて
No way! On December 16th, at Ariake Arena,
アリーナライブ、まじか！まじか！すごいところ！
an arena live, seriously?! Seriously?! Such an incredible place!
12月16日有明アリーナにて、ReGLOSSファーストライブ、「Flash point」の開催が決定しました！
On December 16th at Ariake Arena, the 1st ReGLOSS Live, "Flash point," has been officially announced!
イエーイ！
Yay!
え、現地ライブってことだよね？
Wait, does this mean an in-person live?
そうだよ！
That's right!
しかもめちゃくちゃでかい会場だよ！
Plus, it's a huge venue!
そうだよ、そうだよ、そうだよね！
That's right, that's right, isn't it?!
大変だ！夢が叶うってこと？そうだよね！
This is huge! Does this mean our dream is coming true? That's right!
みんなありがとう！ありがとう！
Thank you everyone! Thank you!
本当、すべてみんなのおかげだね、ありがとう！
It's truly thanks to all of you, thank you!
1個目の夢が叶うかもしれないんだ！
Our first dream might actually come true!
がんばろう！がんばろう！
Let's do our best! Let's do our best!
はい！こちらのライブなんですけれども、セカンドアルバムで描いた世界観に連動して
Yes! For this live, linking with the worldview depicted in our second album,
ReGLOSSの「今」を記憶に焼き付けるというテーマになっています。
the theme is to sear ReGLOSS's "now" into your memories.
つまり、まさに今の私たちの集大成となるライブでございます！
In other words, this will truly be a live that is the culmination of who we are right now!
イエーイ！
Yay!
で、ちょっとね、ライブのキービジュアルも改めてお披露目しちゃいます！
And you know what, we are also unveiling the key visual for the live!
こちらです、ででーん！
Here it is, ta-da!
うわあ！かっこいい！ねえ！
Whoa! So cool! Right?!
今回のキービジュアルはね、ライブのテーマに合わせてライブパフォーマンス中のReGLOSSを切り取ったイメージのデザインとなっています！
This key visual was designed with an image capturing ReGLOSS during their live performance, matching the theme of the concert!
もう、素敵！
It's so wonderful!
なんかまた普段のReGLOSSとは違った一面な感じがしたね。そうそう、雰囲気もね。
It gave a different vibe than usual ReGLOSS, didn't it? Yeah, exactly, the atmosphere too.
今回のライブのハッシュタグは、ハッシュタグReGLOSSアンダーバーファーストライブです！
The hashtag for this live is hashtag ReGLOSS underscore 1st live!
いっぱいポストしてみんなで盛り上がりましょー！お願いします！お願いします！
Please post lots and get hyped together everyone! Please do! Please do!
さて、そんな中、皆様が気になってるであろうチケット情報をね
Now, amidst all that, we'd like to share the ticket information you've all probably been wondering about...
ちょっとみんなにお見せしようかなと思います！チケット情報はちら、ででーん！
Ticket info is right here, ta-da!
はい、えーチケットはS席、A席、B席の3種類です。
Yes, um, tickets come in 3 types: S seats, A seats, and B seats.
一次先行はこのあと、21時からスタートです！
The primary advance lottery starts right after this at 21:00!
先着ではございません、抽選でございます。焦らずにお申し込みください。
It's not first-come, first-served, but a lottery. Please apply without rushing.
さらに、会場には行けないよ、という人のために配信チケットもご用意しました！
Furthermore, for those who can't make it to the venue, we've also prepared streaming tickets!
こちらもこのあと21時から販売開始です。
These also go on sale starting at 21:00.
続いて、会場のエリアマップはこちらです、じゃん！
Next, here is the venue area map, ta-da!
S席、A席、B席がそれぞれどこになるのかはこちらをチェックしてください。
Please check here to see where S seats, A seats, and B seats will be located.
エリアマップはこのあとホロライブ公式Xでもポストするので詳しくはそちらをご確認ください。そしてみんな、歓声トレンド1位！
The area map will also be posted on the official Hololive X account afterwards, so please check there for details. And everyone, trending #1 for cheers!
イエーイ！ありがとう！
Yay! Thank you!
お祝いしてくれて嬉しいな。2周年も、2周年もお祝いしてくれて嬉しいな。
We're so happy you celebrated our 2nd anniversary with us too.
そしてそして、ライブのグッズについては10月1日のレグロス公式YouTubeチャンネルで発表します！
And also, regarding the live merchandise, we will announce it on the official ReGLOSS YouTube channel on October 1st!
楽しみ！楽しみ！素敵なグッズがいっぱいあるので、見逃さないでね！
We're so excited! There are so many wonderful goods, so don't miss out!
そしてそして、今回発表したライブの情報や次回のグッズの情報は特設サイトにて掲載いたします！
And also, the live info and merchandise details announced today will be posted on a special website!
うちらはちょっと事前に見たよね。
We got to see it a little bit beforehand.
見た！見たでしょ？見たよ！
We saw it! You saw it, right? We saw it!
特設サイト、うちらは言ってったかもしれない。
We might have mentioned the special site.
はい、すごくかっこいいサイトなんでぜひとも覗いてみてください。
Yes, it's a really cool site, so please be sure to check it out.
特設サイトは、えっと、ReGLOSSファーストライブ…打ち込んじゃいけんなそれ。
The special site is, um, ReGLOSS 1st live... you shouldn't type that in!
今後も追加情報を更新していくので、ブックマークとチェックよろしくお願いします！
We'll continue updating with more info, so please bookmark and check back!
現地ですってよ！やばいね！どうよみんな？
In-person, they say! That's crazy! What do you think, everyone?
もうリリカはこれもずっとデメルのときから言ってるんだけど
Lilika has been saying this ever since day one,
もうダンスも歌もどっちもやっぱ自信もなかったし、得意じゃないって思ってたリリカがちょっとずつそれぞれを好きになっていけていて
even though Lilika lacked confidence in both dancing and singing and didn't think she was good at it, she's gradually grown to love each of them,
で、みんなにちゃんとその成長した姿を見てもらいたいって思ってて。
and wants everyone to properly see her grown-up self.
そう、その夢が今回のまた新しい現地ライブっていう場で叶うかもしれないって思ったらめちゃくちゃ嬉しいです！
Yeah, thinking that dream might come true in this new venue called an in-person live makes us so happy!
本当にありがとう！
Thank you so much!
え、でも
Um, but...
正直まだ実感がわいてなくて
honestly, it still doesn't really feel real yet...
現地ライブ…！
A live venue concert...!
本当に？本当に！？みたいな。
Like, is this real? Is this really happening!?
なんか実感が本当にわかなくて、
It just doesn't feel real at all,
なんか、ずっとさ、現地ライブしたいしたいって言ってきて、
like, we've been saying for so long "We want to do a live concert!",
いざ決定！ってなって、夢に出て、なんか本当に
and then it was finally decided, and stepping out in front of everyone felt...
不思議な気持ち。
such a surreal feeling.
めちゃめちゃ嬉しいんだけどね！
I'm super happy, of course!
なんか、夢のようで、逆に何も感じないような
But it's like a dream, to the point where I almost feel nothing,
まだ実感がなくて。じわじわあとから
and it still hasn't fully sunk in yet. It's only bit by bit that
うわ、嬉しいってなると思うんだけど、おめでとう、ありがとう！
I'm starting to realize, "Wow, I'm so happy!" Congratulations, and thank you!
みんなのおかげです！
It's all thanks to everyone!
うん、ダンスはどう？ダンス番長？
Yeah. How about you, Dance Bancho?
いや、同じくね、実感がわかなくて、
Well, same here, it doesn't feel real,
なんか本当に何なんだと、夢見心地でよく分からないけど、
like, what is this really? It feels like a fever dream, I don't really get it,
でも、もうあと三ヶ月くらいしたら、
but you know, once another three months pass,
グロッサーのみんなが目の前にいて、
all of you Grossers will be right in front of us,
はじめまして、パフォーマンスやってくれるってことじゃん？
and you'll be putting on performances for us, right?
そのこと、動きも一緒にね、
And that means all your movements along with it—
やってくれるって思ったら、もうすっごい嬉しいでしょ！本当に、応援ありがとうございます！
when I think about you doing all of that, I'm just so happy! Seriously, thank you for your support!
嬉しいね。
That's wonderful.
そしてラデンちゃんは？
And what about you, Raden?
はい、現地ライブということで12月、少し早めのレグラスからのクリスマスプレゼントということで、現地ライブさせていただくんですけれども、
Yes! As for the live venue concert in December, it's a bit of an early Christmas present from ReGLOSS, and we'll be holding a live venue concert,
まさかね、まさかまさかの現地ライブで、
but never did I imagine—never, ever could I have imagined holding a live venue concert.
本当にこんなありがたい機会がいただけることで、生きててなかなか無いじゃない？
To be given such a truly precious opportunity is something you rarely get in life, right?
ないよ、ないよ。
That's true, you don't.
そう、だからすごくありがたいなと思うし、嬉しいなと思うし、今ね、絶賛こう、レッスンでね、
Right, so I feel so grateful and happy. Right now, we're right in the middle of lessons,
ライブに向けて我々頑張っておりますので、ぜひ今後もね、応援してくれるととっても嬉しいです。
working hard toward the live, so we'd be so happy if you continue to support us.
皆さん本当にありがとうございました！
Thank you all so much!
ありがとうございましたー！
Thank you!
ねー、いや本当にライブ嬉しいね。
Yeah, man, I'm really so happy about the live.
最高だね、最高だね。
It's the best. It really is.
でもさ、まあライブのためってわけでもないけどさ、いろんな楽曲を、まあ歌わせていただいていて、
But you know, it's not just for the live, but we've been getting to sing all sorts of different songs,
ま今回、アワタイムイエローもね、新しくリリースさせていただいたわけなんですけれけれども、
and this time, we newly released "Our Time Yellow" as well,
ちょっとその感想も話そうか、ここでね、せっかくだから。
so let's talk about our thoughts on that here, since we have the chance.
話そう、話そう。
Let's do that, let's do that.
じゃあ逆順で行く？
So shall we go in reverse order?
ラデンちゃんどう？
How about you, Raden?
あ、ラデンはね、MV出たじゃん？
Well, Raden, the MV came out, right?
MV出たからもうMVもね、いろんなものが素敵ななんだけど、中でもラデンは歌詞が、すっごい好きで、
Since the MV is out, all of it is wonderful, but among everything, Raden really, really loves the lyrics.
ちょっとMV見て、あ、いい曲だなーとか、なんかMVすごい、あのめちゃめちゃ動いてていいなーって思った方は、もう一回次はね、歌詞にこう注目してくれるとですっごく嬉しいな、なんて思います。
If you watched the MV and thought, "Ah, what a great song," or "The MV moves so much and looks great," I'd be so happy if you could pay attention to the lyrics next time!
うわあ、ありがたいね。
Wow, that's so sweet of you.
番長は？
How about Bancho?
いやもうとにかくリズムとメロディがスキーですね。
Well, simply put, I just love the rhythm and melody.
ちょっとずっとやってる、ちょっと全部失踪感があって、
It's got this driving sense of speed throughout,
なんかこう、その乗ってる言葉のメロディも、全部なんかリズムよかったり、なんかこうチューン、チューンって言ったり、なんかこう激しいやん、移り変わりが、秋の予兆というか、じゃあ
and the melodies of the words on top all have great rhythms, and when it goes "tune, tune," it's so intense, like the signs of autumn transitioning—
なんかもうすっごい、もうメロディ対式っちゅーの。あー、聞いてください。
like, the melody is just so well-crafted. Please give it a listen!
かん、からでもまず曲がものすごく大好きだし、
Well, first off, I just love the song so much,
今日、みんなとさ、初めてMVを見たじゃないですか。
and today, we watched the MV together for the first time, right?
MVをね、見るとなんかすごいかっこいい感じになっていて、なんか大感激でした。
Watching the MV, it looked so cool, and I was deeply moved.
個人的、からねが一番好きなMVシーンは、えー、こういうシーン。
Personally, my favorite scene in the MV is, um... this scene!
どこだろ、どこだろ、どこなんだ、どこなんだろ。
Where is it? Where is it? Where could it be?
一番の終わりだよ、一番の終わり。
At the very end of the first chorus, right at the end of the first chorus.
サビの終わり、サビの終わりのこのモーメントのところだ。ちょ、あそこ、プヨンてやっち、プヨン！
The end of the chorus, that specific moment right at the end of the chorus. Right there, doing that "boing" thing, "boing!"
この日のために、シャンプー頑張りました。
I worked really hard on my shampoo for today's sake.
さらさらね。
So silky-smooth.
リリカは？いやリリカもね、やっぱりアワタイムイエローは
How about Lilika? Well, Lilika too, after all, "Our Time Yellow"
すごくこう、元気になる曲じゃない？テンション上げ上げってなる曲で、すごい聞いてて楽しいし、
is such an energizing song, right? It's a song that gets your spirits up, and it's so much fun to listen to,
あと、踊ってても、すごいねいっぱい激しいところが大好きで、たぶんそんなに失敗しなかったです！
and plus, even when dancing, I love all the intense parts so much. I probably didn't make too many mistakes!
たぶんね。いっぱい練習してくださーい、聞いてくださーい。
Probably. Everyone, please practice hard and give it a listen!
聞いてください！聞いてください！
Please listen to it! Please listen to it!
え、このサビのさ、これめちゃくちゃかっこよくない？ここ、ここ。
Hey, this chorus part—isn't it super cool? Right here, right here.
え、ここ好きなんだよね。あ、わかる、わかる、わかる！
Wait, I love this part. Ah, I know, I know, I know!
ここね。
Right here.
ここ、ここ！こっちゃ、こっちゃ、こっちゃ。ポヨポヨキャット、ニャン。わかる、わかる！
Right here, right here! Over here, over here, over here. Boing-boing cat, meow. I know, I know!
まあね、ちょっと引き続き私たちはアルバムに収録される新曲の練習なんかもね、めちゃくちゃ頑張ってますので、
Well, you know, we're continuing to work super hard practicing the new songs that will be included in the album,
ライブ楽しみにしていてくれたら嬉しいです！
so we'd be so happy if you look forward to the live!
それじゃあ、最後の曲行きますか？
Well then, shall we go to the final song?
最後ですか。いける？
The final one. Can we do it?
え、お水何分くらい？
Um, how many minutes of water?
水なんだろ？
What could it be?
なんだろ？
水なんだろ？
What could it be?
みんな何の曲だと思う？
What song do you think it is?
何歌おうかな？
What song should we sing?
ReGLOSSの曲だったら、やっぱ最後は瞬間ハートビートじゃない？
If it's a ReGLOSS song, the end should be a heart beat, right?
新シンメトリーマンじゃない？
New symmetry, right?
フィーリングラデーションとか違う違う。
Or feeling radiation, or something different.
ちょっと水飲んできわ。
I'll go drink some water.
いってらっしゃい。
Have fun.
やっぱ現地だね。
Well, we're in the venue.
現地もそうだし、あわためいらも出ましたし。
Genchi is also true, and awatami iro came out too.
ね。
Right.
立ち位置着きますか？
Shall we strike a pose?
はい。
Let's go.
いきますか。
Let's do it.
着きましょうか。
Shall we strike a pose?
あれ、こっちということは？
Wait, this way means...
わかる人多分あんまりいないかもしれない。
I guess not many people know this.
え、うちらだけだと思う。
Because it's just us?
あ、そっか。
Ah, right.
立ち位置ここ。
Strike a pose.
こっちからかな。
Is it this way?
聞いてください。
Please listen.
ミッドサマーシトラス。
Mid Summer Citrus.
今日は2周年だから！手を静めよう！
Today is the 2nd anniversary, so let's quieten down!
いけ！
Let's go!
焼け付くような陽射し
Scorching sunlight,
水面に浮かぶスパンコール
Sequins floating on the water's surface,
眩（くら）む夏色と逆光の裏側で
In the backlight behind the vibrant summer,
あの日の青春を呼び覚ましている
Awakening the youth of that day.
デニムの裾を捲くって
Rolling up the hem of denim,
裸足で走ってる砂の上
Running barefoot on the sand,
硝子の淵で回り回るがが
Spinning round and round at the edge of the glass,
耀く瑠璃色のビー玉
Shiny lapis lazuli-colored marble.
なんだかその笑顔と紙一重だね
Somehow, it's a fine line from your smile.
フィルムを覗けばノンフィクション
If you look through the film, it's non-fiction,
彩りに絆されたメモリー
Memories bound by colors.
リセットなんてできないから
Because I can't reset it,
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance to midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
In the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Cut out the joys and sorrows.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love,
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it.
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の思い出
Memories for a lifetime with you,
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
love yourself just as you are now
氷が溶けては渦巻いた
Ice melting and swirling,
魔法の杖代わりのマドラー
A muddler acting as a magic wand.
喉の奥くすぐる炭酸
Carbonation tickling the back of the throat,
薫る柑橘系のフレーバー
Fragrant citrus flavor.
爽やかな気流にのって
Riding on the refreshing airflow,
波の還りを見守っている beachside
Watching the waves return to the beachside.
あどけない面影に焦がれ
Longing for the innocent appearance,
微かに触れそうな指先
Fingertips that seem to touch faintly,
煌めきで上書きしてしまおう
Let's paint over it with brilliance.
get ahead of what you used to be
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance to midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
In the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Cut out the joys and sorrows.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love,
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it.
ミッドサマーシトラス oh yeah
Midsummer Citrus, oh yeah,
いつだって we got love!! okay
Always we got love!! okay.
キミといるだけで
Just being with you,
feel so nice ココロはまた実り
Feel so nice, my heart blooms again.
寝起きの太陽も
Even the waking sun,
願ってもない絢爛日和？
A brilliant day that I couldn't ask for?
白飛びしてしまうほど
It's because of summer,
眩いのは夏のせい
That it's dazzling enough to blow out.
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance to midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
In the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Cut out the joys and sorrows.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love,
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it.
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の思い出
Memories for a lifetime with you,
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance to midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
In the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Cut out the joys and sorrows.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love,
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it.
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の思い出
Memories for a lifetime with you,
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
ミッドサマーシトラス おやっ！
Midsummer Citrus! Oh yeah!
いつだってウェイクアップ！
It's time to wake up!
キミといるだけで
Just being with you,
feel so nice ココロはまた実り
My heart blooms again,
寝起きの太陽も
Even the waking sun,
願ってもない燦々日和？
A brilliant day that I couldn't ask for?
白飛びしてしまうほど
It's because of summer,
眩いのは夏のせい
That it's dazzling enough to blow out.
love yourself just as you are now
踊ってミッドサマー
Dance to midsummer,
アルゴリズムの中
In the algorithm,
瞬息でダビングして
Dubbing in an instant,
切り取って喜怒哀楽
Cut out the joys and sorrows.
これがきっと愛だ
This must be love,
二度と忘れないように
So I'll never forget it.
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の思い出
Memories for a lifetime with you,
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
love yourself just as you are now
le lemon lime orange
キミと一生分の思い出
Memories for a lifetime with you,
何気ない一日が one of a kind
A casual day is one of a kind.
love yourself just as you are now
ありがとー！
Thank you!
12月16日、みんな楽しみにしてるよー！
December 16th, everyone, look forward to it.
有明アリーナも、配信も！
ARIAKE ARENA and streaming, everyone!
全員で盛り上がろうねー！
Let's all have fun!
これからも楽しもうね！
Let's have fun together!
時間があれば、もっとたくさん聴いてください！
If you have time, please come listen to a lot!
せーの、ReGLOSSでした！
We are ReGLOSS!
現地でお会いしましょう！
Let's meet in person!